613-921-6990 ncard24@gmail.com

PROFILE

Highly motivated Front End developer changing careers after multiple years of owning and operating my own business. I have a passion for Front End development I specialize in React and TypeScript. With a great working knowledge in Back End technologies Node.js, MongoDB, Express.js

LANGUAGES/FRAMEWORKS/TOOLS/SKILLS

JavaScript (ES6), CSS, HTML, SQL, React, TailWindCSS, Node.js, Express, Next.js, TypeScript, Git, Github, JSON, Jest, GCP, Redux, Webpack, APIs, NPM, Firebase

PROJECTS

Microblog Platform — TypeScript, PostgreSQL, React, TailwindCSS, OAuth

A type safe social media site with reusable custom built React components, user authentication via OAuth. Using SQL functions the data for messages, responses, and likes is stored on a Supabase PostgreSQL database. I used TailwindCSS to create a responsive layout from mobile phones up to 4k monitors, included a dark mode based on user system preferences.

E-commerce Store — TypeScript, React, TailwindCSS

A type safe e-commerce store using a Shopify product API for test products. The store is complete through to the checkout process, featuring individual item pages using reusable React components, it has a fully responsive layout for mobile phone shopping experiences.

EDUCATION

The Odin Project — 2023 — Remote

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Trent University — 2011-2015 — Peterborough, ON

History BA Honours

University of Birmingham — 2013 — Birmingham, England

Study Abroad

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Co-Founder/Head of Operations

Wild Card Brewing Co. Trenton, ON - 2015-2023

Managed and maintained website using HTML and CSS skills, implementing inventory management

- system and launched e-commerce store in 2019
- E-commerce store was used by almost 1500 visitors a day in April 2020, with a 5% conversion rate
- Operated and managed a production brewery with over \$0.5M in annual revenue, overseeing inventory, costs, quality control, and compliance
- Launched brand into province-wide distribution within four years of operation, coordinating with governmental agencies, logistic companies, and other stakeholders

Finance Co-ordinator

MASS Environmental Services Inc Cobourg, ON - 2019-2022

- Prepared financial reports and statements for senior management using Quickbooks and Excel
- Processed invoices for data entry and backups ensuring timely recording of transactions

Waste Auditor / Technical Services Co-ordinator

MASS Environmental Services Inc Cobourg, ON — 2017-2019

- Completed waste audit reports for clients across various industries, improving format of reporting to enhance clarity and efficiency in data analysis
- Coordinated technical support activities with nation wide locations and companies, troubleshooting issues, arranging repairs, and liaising with staff and vendors to ensure customer satisfaction



Scan to visit portfolio site